Thanks for coming back.
شكرًا لعودتكم.
So we have a couple of cakes already.
يوجد لدينا قطعتي كيك بالفعل.
But you know, can you ever have too many cakes?
لكن كما تعلمون، هل حصلتم على العديد من قطع الكيك قبل ذلك؟
That was a rhetorical question, the answer is obviously no.
كان هذا سؤال مجازي، ومن الواضح أن الجواب لا.
So in light of this delicious fact,
إذن في ضوء هذه الحقيقة اللذيذة،
let's make another cake.
هيا نصنع قطعة كيك أخرى.
But we've learned from lesson one that if I make the cake,
لكننا تعلمنا في الدرس الأول أنني إذا صنعت الكيك،
it'll be downright ugly.
فإنها ستكون سيئة للغاية.
If I let a professional make it,
وإذا تركت شخصًا محترفًا يصنعها،
then it'll look amazing, but there'll be no love or personality in it.
فسوف تبدو مذهلة، ولكنها تفتقد الحب والطابع الشخصي.
This next cake needs the love and care from
فتحتاج قطعة الكيك الثانية هذه إلى الحب والعناية
the first cake and the quality of the second cake.
التي تتميز بها القطعة الأولى وجودة القطعة الثانية.
Oh, well, hi Miriam.
حسنًا، مرحبًا يا ميريام.
Hi there.
مرحبًا!
Can you tell us a little bit about what you do here in Udacity.
هل يمكن أن تخبرينا قليلاً عما تفعلينه هنا في Udacity.
Yeah, I work on our mentorship programs to help
نعم، أعمل على برامج الإرشاد الخاصة بنا للمساعدة
support student learning and improve their experience.
على دعم الطلاب في التعلم وتحسين خبرتهم.
That's really amazing, Miriam.
هذا رائع حقًا يا ميريام.
You do so much for the student community,
أنت تقدمين الكثير جدًا لمجتمع الطلاب
and I know they really appreciate it.
وأعرف أنهم يقدرون ذلك حقًا.
But I also know that you have some other hobbies as well.
ولكنني أعرف أيضًا أن لديك هوايات أخرى كذلك.
Yeah, let's see, among other things I bake a lot for the office.
نعم، دعنا نرى، من بين أمور أخرى، أقوم بخبز قطع كيك كثيرة للمكتب.
And it's awesome. I mean, really,
وتكون رائعة. أعني حقًا أن
everything she makes disappears instantly.
كل شيء تصنعه يختفي على الفور.
Thank you so much.
شكرًا جزيلاً.
So, I was wondering,
كنت أتساءل،
my mom's birthday is coming up.
يقترب عيد ميلاد والدتي.
Would you mind making a cake for her?
فهلا صنعتِ قطعة كيك لها؟
Oh my gosh. I would be honored.
يا إلهي. أتشرف بذلك.
That's awesome. Thanks so much, Miriam.
هذا رائع. شكرًا جزيلاً يا ميريام.
She will love it.
سوف تحبها.
I hope so. I'll go get baking.
أتمنى ذلك. سأذهب وأحضر الخبز.
Asking Miriam to bake a cake for me is just like
إن الطلب من ميريام أن تصنع قطعة كيك لي أمر يشبه
the new technology we'll be looking at in this lesson.
التقنية الجديدة التي سننظر فيها في هذا الدرس.
I'm not doing the work,
فأنا لا أقوم بفعل العمل،
I just make the request,
وإنما أطلبه فقط
and I don't have to load some professional library like
ولست مضطرًا لتحميل بعض المكتبات المهنية مثل
jQuery because this new tool is provided right in the browser.
واجهة برمجة التطبيقات jQuery لأن هذه الأداة الجديدة متوفرة مباشرةً في المتصفح.
So, what is this life-changing tech?
إذن، ما هذه التقنية المغيرة للحياة؟
Drum roll please.
استعدوا رجاءً.
I give you the Fetch API.
أقدم لكم واجهة برمجة تطبيقات الإحضار.
So, yeah, the name isn't all that impressive-sounding,
حسنًا، ليس الاسم هو الأمر المرموق المثير للإعجاب،
but Fetch really is an amazing tool that will change how you
بل إن الإحضار يمثل حقًا أداة رائعة ستغير طريقتك في
write asynchronous requests. Let's see how it works.
كتابة الطلبات غير المتزامنة. هيا نرى طريقة عملها.